<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eleanor Graham</title>
    <description>I&#39;m learning things. You can join me.
</description>
    <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://eleanorgraham.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 13:48:24 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 13:48:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gem and the Rock(climb)ers</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;presenting-hiking-guide&quot;&gt;Presenting: Hiking Guide&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../images/hit_the_trails.png&quot; alt=&quot;hit the trails!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just finished building a Command Line Interface(CLI) Gem called &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubygems.org/gems/hiking_guide&quot;&gt;Hiking Guide&lt;/a&gt;. It grabs information on hiking trails in the US mid-Atlantic off of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hikingupward.com/&quot;&gt;HikingUpward&lt;/a&gt; and presents that information to the user on the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why&quot;&gt;But Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m working through the Flatiron school’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.co/&quot;&gt;Learn&lt;/a&gt; curriculum, and building a CLI Gem is the final project for the section on Object Oriented Ruby. Coming up with a topic and a site to scrape is all up to us, and I decided to use my beautiful home — the Shenandoah Valley — as inspiration. I don’t really expect anyone else to use my little gem (is anyone besides me really interested in looking up hiking trail details from the command line?). Still, after spending so much time staring at my computer screen, I knew I could really benefit from hitting the trails and that was reason enough for me to proceed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;challenges&quot;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web scraping turned out to be much more difficult than I anticipated. HikingUpward is a volunteer organization — this means that the website is maintained by multiple people, and the information presented there is anything but consistent. There were several times that I almost gave up and picked a different topic/project. One particular volunteer in NC added some fancy script to his trail descriptions that required a method all its own to clean up (Hi, Zach! Thanks for the challenge and added hours!) — and I almost decided to just leave NC trails off the list entirely because of this. But I didn’t — I kept at it and figured it out. It’s hard to describe how satisfying that felt!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also challenged myself to write some tests for the first time, which was great fun. It’s a skill I want to develop, but haven’t had the reason to really push myself. Although I don’t have anything close to full test coverage for this project, the few tests I do have are a good step for me (and it leaves me something to come back to and improve!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;good-enough&quot;&gt;Good Enough&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that keeps me interested in coding is the seemingly endless possibility for improvement. Once I start thinking about a puzzle I have a hard time putting it down; I keep turning it over and over, polishing, refining. So, although I’m calling this gem ‘ready’ I have ideas for things I could improve, should the time and desire present itself. I also have a bundle of ideas for other projects that I feel ready to take on in the wake of this success. It feels good to say that what I’ve created is good enough and release it into the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 14:28:12 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/gem-and-the-rockclimbers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/gem-and-the-rockclimbers/</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
        <category>ruby gems</category>
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pairing</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;two-heads&quot;&gt;Two heads…&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I had my first pair programming experience. Up until that point, I had been working through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.co/&quot;&gt;Learn&lt;/a&gt; curriculum on my own with very little outside interaction. Then I hit one of the final projects in the Object Oriented Ruby section: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/learn-co-students/ttt-with-ai-project-v-000&quot;&gt;Tic Tac Toe with Artificial Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;. The assignment strongly encouraged us to find pairs. I had misgivings about it: How would I find someone right at the same part of the curriculum as me? How would we schedule around my childcare and other work duties? What if I ended up with a terrible partner? It sounded like a lot of extra work…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flashback-the-dreaded-group-project&quot;&gt;Flashback: the dreaded group project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lernaean_Hydra&quot;&gt;Hydra&lt;/a&gt;. That’s how I feel about academic group projects. I was a non-traditional student (read: older than my classmates) when I was finishing my Bachelor’s degree. Although I was a musician, specializing in chamber music collaboration, I dreaded group projects in my academic classes. There was so much extra work — scheduling meetings, encouraging the other group members, and then redoing all their work at the last minute to make it presentable (yes, I was that student). Was this pair programming going to be like that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;two-heads-are-better-than-one&quot;&gt;Two heads… &lt;em&gt;are better&lt;/em&gt; than one&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t like that – no Hydras to battle here. Of course, that’s partly due to the fact that I was lucky enough to end up with a fabulous partner (Hi, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kkterai&quot;&gt;Kenlyn&lt;/a&gt; – you are a delight!). It felt so good working together and talking through the code. Finally I wasn’t alone in front of my screen anymore. Finally there was someone else wrestling with the same puzzles at the same time. Even the act of talking about the questions we faced helped unravel them. Everything about the experience was valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only was the process a great learning experience – we ended up producing a project that was better than either of us would have come up with on our own. As we worked, we pulled the best from each other and refined things further. When we wrapped up I felt energized and excited about future collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 10:28:12 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/pairing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/pairing/</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
        <category>pair programming</category>
        
        <category>collaboration</category>
        
        <category>tic tac toe</category>
        
        <category>games</category>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dry Eloquence</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;dry-dont-repeat-yourself&quot;&gt;DRY: Don’t Repeat Yourself.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmers talk about the virtues of DRY code, as opposed to WET (We Enjoy Typing! Write Everything Twice!). The virtue goes beyond funny acronyms: code that eliminates unnecessary repetition is easier for an outsider to read and understand. It’s also easier to extend functionality as the program grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;understanding-vs-doing&quot;&gt;Understanding vs Doing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the value of writing DRY code, and actually doing it are two different things. Although I long for simple and eloquent code, usually my first solutions are anything but DRY. And this may be a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school I remember a math teacher getting frustrated with me for not writing enough steps in my solutions - “Show your work!” Some of the steps seemed so simple I couldn’t bring myself to write them down – I could already see several steps ahead, and at the time I felt embarrassed to show such elementary ‘extra’ work. Not only did I frustrate my teacher with this stubbornness, but I made things more difficult for myself: when things didn’t turn out as planned, it was harder to catch mistakes in the assumptions that I had left unwritten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-wet-road-to-dry&quot;&gt;The (WET) road to DRY&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I try getting too far ahead of myself with coding I end up tangling things up. If I can allow myself to ‘write everything twice’ just to get initial tests passing, I usually have a much easier time simplifying from there. Starting out WET is only a problem if you never dry off.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 09:28:12 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/dry-eloquence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/dry-eloquence/</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
        <category>technique</category>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>100 Days of Commits</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8522/28946125041_e0c371b160_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Commits&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@WomenWhoCodeDC/100-days-of-commits-60af0abe8825#.mflpf9vke&quot;&gt;100 Days of Commits&lt;/a&gt; just a few days before it began. I decided to join in without giving it much thought. Now, 13 days in, I’d like to reflect a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;yay&quot;&gt;Yay&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First: Hooray! 13 days in a row of commits is probably twice as long as any previous streak for me. Already I’ve learned a lot, even with my completely haphazard unplanned approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning&quot;&gt;Learning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jumping in with no planning means that I’ve been forced to go with low hanging fruit. Those changes that I’ve been wanting to make to my website? Now’s the time! That new thing I’ve been curious about? Dig in! So far I’ve learned more about Jekyll and Mapbox. I’ve also learned about my own workflow and have made some improvements that feel good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also been so fun to feel the buoyancy of doing this practice together with so many other people. Even though I’ve just been working on my own stuff so far (no collaborate contributions yet), it makes me so happy to see the other participants progressing. Check out the activity on twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/100Commits&quot;&gt;@100Commits&lt;/a&gt;) – it’s great!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 11:28:12 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/100-days-of-commits/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/100-days-of-commits/</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
        <category>100-days-of-commits</category>
        
        <category>women-who-code</category>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Framing</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;parenting--programming&quot;&gt;Parenting || Programming…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My daughter is almost two. She’s hilarious and wonderful. She is a girl who loves to explore. She loves trucks and getting dirty in the garden just as much as she loves dolls and reading books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8008/28853192845_b7ba691593_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;finger painting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I watch her learn and interact with the world I’m continually struck by the impact of framing. The way that I frame things is helping her form her worldview; my interpretations inform the way she thinks about herself and her own possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine we’re playing together. She grabs a cardboard box and starts putting other items into it. I could say, &lt;em&gt;“Oh! Are you cooking up some soup in your kitchen?”&lt;/em&gt; I could also say, &lt;em&gt;“Oh! Are you doing an experiment in your lab?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a big difference. I hear the outside world giving my daughter a personal vocabulary that leans heavily towards &lt;em&gt;purses&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;babydolls&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;playing house&lt;/em&gt;. I am going to do my best to diversify her vocabulary and broaden her horizons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this have to do with programming?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;variables--vocabulary&quot;&gt;Variables = Vocabulary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we build our programs, we give them a vocabulary. The variables that we write into our programs become a way for them to store data and communicate about that data. Every time we create a new variable, it would behoove us to consider the underlying assumptions that we’re building into our program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;methods--behaviors&quot;&gt;Methods = Behaviors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The methods we write determine the behavior within our programs. Defining new methods broadens the possible actions. Again, our decisions create a frame of possibilities within the world of our program. What frame are we creating?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 15:28:12 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/framing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/framing/</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
        <category>parenting</category>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Texture of Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://api.mapbox.com/styles/v1/eleanorgraham/cirdsie72000lg9ng6g9d088g/static/-79.115266,38.142616,11.26,0.00,0.00/600x600?access_token=pk.eyJ1IjoiZWxlYW5vcmdyYWhhbSIsImEiOiJjaW93NTR0ZHIwMWVmdWVtNXl5aTZqcW5tIn0.jSLqL9vRKByhoSH9l8E7qA&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;A Mapbox map of Staunton, VA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;birds-eye-view&quot;&gt;Bird’s Eye View&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always loved riding in planes. I love looking at the patchwork below, seeing if I can identify any parts of the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at this map reminds me of that. How the the reaching tendrils of country roads spread from central veins; how the denser grid forms, showing a patch of city… It has a texture. I want to touch it like a quilt – feel the grooves with my fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could, I would be touching the texture of my own landscape. Feeling home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://api.mapbox.com/styles/v1/eleanorgraham/cirdsie72000lg9ng6g9d088g/static/-79.080000,38.147000,12.83,0.00,0.00/600x600@2x?access_token=pk.eyJ1IjoiZWxlYW5vcmdyYWhhbSIsImEiOiJjaW93NTR0ZHIwMWVmdWVtNXl5aTZqcW5tIn0.jSLqL9vRKByhoSH9l8E7qA&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;A closer view of the Staunton, VA Mapbox map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zooming in, I look for my house. I can see the shapes. I recognize the little slip of a street we live on. I see the broader strokes all around us. I find the curves and contours mesmerizing. The grids shift around our hills. The streets and rails converge. Beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maps above are my first foray into playing with my own styling in Mapbox. It’s really fun. I can’t wait to dig in more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 13:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/topography/texture-of-home/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/topography/texture-of-home/</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>maps</category>
        
        <category>Mapbox</category>
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
        <category>stories</category>
        
        <category>home</category>
        
        
        <category>topography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mapping Home</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-topography&quot;&gt;Personal Topography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always loved maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;600&quot; src=&quot;https://api.mapbox.com/v4/mapbox.outdoors/-79.0717,38.1496,13/600x300@2x.png?access_token=pk.eyJ1IjoiZWxlYW5vcmdyYWhhbSIsImEiOiJjaW93NTR0ZHIwMWVmdWVtNXl5aTZqcW5tIn0.jSLqL9vRKByhoSH9l8E7qA&quot; alt=&quot;Mapbox Map of -79.0717, 38.1496&quot; /&gt;
© &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mapbox.com/map-feedback/&quot;&gt;Mapbox&lt;/a&gt; © &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openstreetmap.org/copyright&quot;&gt;OpenStreetMap contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think of so much of my personal history in terms of maps. The worn map I used when I lived in Berlin to pick my bike routes. The tourist map of Prague that magically showed me the tiny street I needed. The map in the kitchen at my grandparent’s house in Hull, showing the beach where we swam and the harbor that we could see out the window…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to start telling the stories of these maps. It’s a two-fold project. On the technical side, I want to experiment with new tools – design and build the maps in my imagination. On a personal level, I want to capture some of these stories. I want to explore the places of my memory in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are. Staunton is my home now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;600&quot; src=&quot;https://api.mapbox.com/v4/mapbox.outdoors/-79.0717,38.1450,15/600x300@2x.png?access_token=pk.eyJ1IjoiZWxlYW5vcmdyYWhhbSIsImEiOiJjaW93NTR0ZHIwMWVmdWVtNXl5aTZqcW5tIn0.jSLqL9vRKByhoSH9l8E7qA&quot; alt=&quot;Mapbox Map of -79.0717, 38.1450&quot; /&gt;
© &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mapbox.com/map-feedback/&quot;&gt;Mapbox&lt;/a&gt; © &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openstreetmap.org/copyright&quot;&gt;OpenStreetMap contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This small map contains the streets where I make my home and do my work; the bridge I walk over and the farmer’s market where I buy veggies; the shops and restaurants around my home… There is so much significance for me within the contours of these lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you can’t see it yet. But I’ll show you. Soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 14:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/topography/maps/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/topography/maps/</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>maps</category>
        
        <category>Mapbox</category>
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
        <category>stories</category>
        
        
        <category>topography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strength in Diversity</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;cheers-to-women-in-tech&quot;&gt;Cheers to Women In Tech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most recent episode of Front End Happy Hour is all about &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontendhappyhour.com/episodes/raise-your-glass-to-women-in-tech/&quot;&gt;Women In Tech&lt;/a&gt; – a topic near and dear to my heart. There was a lot of talk about unconscious bias and ways to encourage diversity. It was good to hear the group agree wholeheartedly that increasing diversity in tech leads to more perspectives, greater innovation, and all around better products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-does-diversity-look-like&quot;&gt;What does Diversity look like?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s explore this. What does it look like for an existing company to develop this promised strength in diversity? It takes more than talk. It takes more than hiring a token #{diverse_person}. There needs to be a shift in culture – a true embrace of the challenges that come with diversification…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;challenges&quot;&gt;Challenges?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While diversity is proven to yield wonderful results, no one said it would be easy. Homogeneity usually feels easier – if everyone thinks in the same way, that often leads to speedy consensus. The fastest route may not be the best, however. In this case, it’s important to work through any potential discomfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a true embrace of diversity a company is saying that they want more perspectives, more ideas. This means teams need to develop respectful processes for working through different opinions and finding ways forward. Team members need to develop open minds and empathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A company can only benefit from diverse perspectives if it makes them truly welcome in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 10:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/diversity/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/diversity/</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>diversity</category>
        
        <category>women</category>
        
        <category>collaboration</category>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I love Amethyst</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;adventures-with-an-automatic-tiling-window-manager&quot;&gt;Adventures with an automatic tiling window manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone new to web development, I was overwhelmed by the number of windows necessary for basic tasks. All the juggling! Switching back and forth between windows; sizing them so that I could work; placing them where they wouldn’t get lost underneath one another… It felt like an irritating waste of time and energy — lots of clicking and lag — especially when things changed (maybe this window should be bigger now, but maybe that throws off the whole organizing system)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps an ideal workspace would include multiple large monitors so that I could stretch out — but that’s not always an option. Even if I could set up some sprawling workspace at home, I also like to be able to work elsewhere. So. Enter: an automatic tiling window manager. Imagine something that would automatically place your windows on the screen for you, side by side, so that you can see everything. Imagine being able to change layouts, focus, sizes, etc. all with simple key commands. It’s magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ianyh/Amethyst&quot;&gt;Amethyst&lt;/a&gt;. I haven’t tried any of the other ones because I’m so satisfied with how Amethyst supports my workflow. Let me give you a little tour:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four different layouts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tall&quot;&gt;Tall&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7338/28134638695_7b50523f55.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tall Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wide&quot;&gt;Wide&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7546/28134639215_126d1a534a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wide Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;fullscreen&quot;&gt;Fullscreen&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7401/27853357720_2f64d2c0ef.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fullscreen Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;column&quot;&gt;Column&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7308/28134638355_9beceed7f8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Column Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— all of which you can easily switch between with key commands. When you open a window it automatically swoops into position, arranging itself amongst the others according to the layout you’ve chosen. Shift + Option + Space will cycle you through all possible layouts when you want to switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to spend the most time in the Tall layout. When I’m there sometimes I want my main window at the left to be larger: Shift + Option + l&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7318/28030885452_d1c0d8470b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tall-left Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and sometimes I want the other windows on the right to be larger: Shift + Option + h&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7393/27853358400_af96403ed1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tall-right Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also shift my focus with key commands. Say I’m editing my text in sublime text and I want to shift my focus to the browser to refresh and see my work. Shift + Option + k moves focus clockwise and Shift + Option + j moves focus counter clockwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more commands — ones for changing which window is in the main slot, etc. I suggest getting used to a few key commands first and then expanding from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m amazed at how easily I have come to rely on this, and how frustrating it feels to be on a machine that doesn’t have it. Having an automatic tiling window manager feels like having a personal assistant dedicated to keeping me in the flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to learning!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 10:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/i-love-amethyst/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/i-love-amethyst/</guid>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
        <category>Amethyst</category>
        
        <category>tools</category>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>why dev?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7293/27420668330_96666a0036.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Split Screen&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7417/27088517983_673fb73372.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lucy with book in box&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-i-decide-to-learn-software-development&quot;&gt;Why did I decide to learn software development?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One answer is that it feels good. My particular blend of curiosity, creativity, and analytical thought lends itself to the puzzles of a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next answer is that I am a mother. Not only that — I am mother to a young daughter. I want to participate in shaping her world. I can show her what it looks like to challenge myself, learn, and grow. I can show her that we can do more than be passive users of technology; we can build and shape it. I can show her that diversity matters. I can help her learn to write her own narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I want to feel satisfied at the end of the day. I want to know the I’ve collaborated and accomplished something I care about. I want to love my work and have it support my family. I think I can find that in software development. So I’m learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 20:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/why-dev/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/why-dev/</guid>
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
        <category>parenting</category>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
