<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eleanor Graham</title>
    <description>I&#39;m learning things. You can join me. 
</description>
    <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://eleanorgraham.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 15:39:50 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 15:39:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>I love Amethyst</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;adventures-with-an-automatic-tiling-window-manager&quot;&gt;Adventures with an automatic tiling window manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone new to web development, I was overwhelmed by the number of windows necessary for basic tasks. All the juggling! Switching back and forth between windows; sizing them so that I could work; placing them where they wouldn’t get lost underneath one another… It felt like an irritating waste of time and energy — lots of clicking and lag — especially when things changed (maybe this window should be bigger now, but maybe that throws off the whole organizing system)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps an ideal workspace would include multiple large monitors so that I could stretch out — but that’s not always an option. Even if I could set up some sprawling workspace at home, I also like to be able to work elsewhere. So. Enter: an automatic tiling window manager. Imagine something that would automatically place your windows on the screen for you, side by side, so that you can see everything. Imagine being able to change layouts, focus, sizes, etc. all with simple key commands. It’s magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ianyh/Amethyst&quot;&gt;Amethyst&lt;/a&gt;. I haven’t tried any of the other ones because I’m so satisfied with how Amethyst supports my workflow. Let me give you a little tour:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four different layouts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tall&quot;&gt;Tall&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7338/28134638695_7b50523f55.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tall Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wide&quot;&gt;Wide&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7546/28134639215_126d1a534a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wide Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;fullscreen&quot;&gt;Fullscreen&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7401/27853357720_2f64d2c0ef.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fullscreen Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;column&quot;&gt;Column&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7308/28134638355_9beceed7f8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Column Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— all of which you can easily switch between with key commands. When you open a window it automatically swoops into position, arranging itself amongst the others according to the layout you’ve chosen. Shift + Option + Space will cycle you through all possible layouts when you want to switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to spend the most time in the Tall layout. When I’m there sometimes I want my main window at the left to be larger: Shift + Option + l&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7318/28030885452_d1c0d8470b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tall-left Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and sometimes I want the other windows on the right to be larger: Shift + Option + h&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7393/27853358400_af96403ed1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tall-right Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also shift my focus with key commands. Say I’m editing my text in sublime text and I want to shift my focus to the browser to refresh and see my work. Shift + Option + k moves focus clockwise and Shift + Option + j moves focus counter clockwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more commands — ones for changing which window is in the main slot, etc. I suggest getting used to a few key commands first and then expanding from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m amazed at how easily I have come to rely on this, and how frustrating it feels to be on a machine that doesn’t have it. Having an automatic tiling window manager feels like having a personal assistant dedicated to keeping me in the flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to learning!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 10:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/2016/07/06/i-love-amethyst.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/2016/07/06/i-love-amethyst.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>why dev?</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;photos&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7293/27420668330_96666a0036.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-half&quot; alt=&quot;Split Screen&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7417/27088517983_673fb73372.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-half&quot; alt=&quot;Lucy with book in box&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-i-decide-to-learn-software-development&quot;&gt;Why did I decide to learn software development?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One answer is that it feels good. My particular blend of curiosity, creativity, and analytical thought lends itself to the puzzles of a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next answer is that I am a mother. Not only that — I am mother to a young daughter. I want to participate in shaping her world. I can show her what it looks like to challenge myself, learn, and grow. I can show her that we can do more than be passive users of technolgy; we can build and shape it. I can show her that diversity matters. I can help her learn to write her own narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I want to feel satisfied at the end of the day. I want to know the I’ve collaborated and accomplished something I care about. I want to love my work and have it support my family. I think I can find that in software development. So I’m learning.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 20:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/2016/06/15/why-dev.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/2016/06/15/why-dev.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We&#39;re Live!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;commit&quot;&gt;Commit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started playing with Jekyll almost a month ago. Today I decided that it was time to make this experiment public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago I had a blogger blog, and then moved on to wordpress with my own url. For a while I had fun with wordpress, modifying templates and playing around with periodic redesigns…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in 2013 I became dissatisfied. I wanted to understand what was going on underneath. I wanted to build my own structures. And I wasn’t too sure about what I wanted public anymore either. So I tore down my wordpress site and put up a single static page. It looked like &lt;a href=&quot;/landing.html&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My site sat like that until February 2016, when I decided to move it and host my site on Github. It still looked the same, but I knew the difference. I knew that I was getting ready to start experimenting again, and this was the first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;today&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here we are today. Jekyll up and running. I am buzzing with ideas of how I want to modify and build this space. It feels good and creative.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 09:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/2016/06/02/live.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/2016/06/02/live.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making Art</title>
        <description>&lt;h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Painting, Mama!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photos&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7142/27041098545_920ddd25f1_k.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-half&quot; alt=&quot;Painting on the window&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chamber Music - duet with Bluppo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photos&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7309/27007842956_9191db0108_k.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-half&quot; alt=&quot;Playing the piano&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 22:04:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/liberty-house/2016/05/15/making-art.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/liberty-house/2016/05/15/making-art.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>liberty-house</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In the Garden</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My girl makes mud soup 
&lt;br /&gt;dirt in her hair, she explores 
&lt;br /&gt;our garden, the world&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;photos&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7350/26948610091_c04b4c1371_z.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-half&quot; alt=&quot;Garden&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 20:16:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/liberty-house/2016/05/14/in-the-garden.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/liberty-house/2016/05/14/in-the-garden.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>liberty-house</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day Two</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m back. I’m challenging myself to post often; to find a rhythm, establish a workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while back I was following along with Sarah J Bray and her Hot Dates with your website curriculum. One of her characters was “Mo” - Momentum. It’s time for me to get reaquainted with Mo. Inertia is deadly. If I’m already in motion, I don’t need to waste energy on getting moving – I can focus on direction and style and any number of other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So. Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 20:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/2016/05/11/day-two.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/2016/05/11/day-two.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello, Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing out Jekyll… I expect to go back and add more blog content later – for now, I’d just like to see how all of this works! Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 20:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/2016/05/10/hello-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eleanorgraham.com/learn-log/2016/05/10/hello-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>learn-log</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
